RACHIT CHADHA

rachitch@terpmail.umd.edu | +1 240-554-7989 | linkedin.com/in/rachitchadha | github.com/rachit-chadha/Data-Science

Summary

Data enthusiast with experience in applying data science techniques for identifying and delivering business improvement projects to develop asset management capabilities and generate actionable insights. My portfolio of accomplishments includes Database Design, Cloud Computing, Data Modeling, Dashboard Development, API Integration, and Technical Consulting.

Education

University of Maryland | College Park, MD

Graduation 05/2020

Major: B.S. Computer And Information Sciences | Concentration: Data Science

*Semester Academic Honors - GPA 3.94 Spring 2020

Relevant Courses: Database Design & Modeling (A-) | Advanced Data Science(A+) | Technology Infrastructure and Architecture (A) | Data Visualization (A+) | Decision Making Analysis (A-) | Competitive Business Intelligence (A) | Privacy & Ethics Big Data (A) | Certifications: Institute of Asset Management Certification | Google Digital Marketing | Oracle Primavera Project Management

Skills

Experience

Turner & Townsend AMCL New York NY Data & Analytics Consultant 04/2022 – Present

- Leading data analytics for capital projects with the US Housing and Urban Development for New York City Housing Authority's 178,000 housing assets
- Created dynamic dashboards for a \$3.3 Billion asset cluster using Power BI, sourcing through SQL management servers and Azure Virtual machines to Monitor and improve NYCHA's asset management capabilities
- Data migration and manipulation with PowerBI DAX, MDX, and Python Pandas for designing performance metrics to track asset outage, performance, and cost
- Develop automated python scripts to scrape and cluster periodic email reports for asset condition information using python SharePlum, pandas and sci-kit learn
- Automated weather data sourcing from Weather-Underground to monitor precipitation impacts using Python's Selenium library hosted on Google Cloud.

Aegis Project Controls Washington DC Project Controls Engineer 08/2020 – 03/2022

- Consulted clients on multiple engineering projects related to energy, education, and government with individual projects valued at over \$200M
- Designed automated Dashboards using PowerBI and power query, to generate insights and recommendations on project health, cost, and progress.
- Developed Python script to collect contractor project data to source from SQL hosted server to virtual cloud environment

University of Maryland College Park MD Analytics Research Assistant 08/2019 – 05/2020

- Designed a web simulation with an agile approach that teaches cybersecurity and collaboration in STEM, funded by the National Science Foundation
- Devised a learning analytics system using REST API interface with Python and MySQL, and integrated it into the University's AWS infrastructure
- Spearheaded a research initiative to scrape, visualize, and present game mechanics' data to Brigham Young and Indiana partner universities

Intel Corporation
Singapore
Marketing Analyst Intern – eSports
05/2019 - 08/2019

- Formulated project plan for Intel Extreme Masters 2020 to increase reach across Asia Pacific's 40 Million eSports viewers
- Developed, managed, and executed 2 product strategy campaigns for APJ and ANZ regions within the Games and eSports team
- Scraped, analyzed, and visualized data for the eSports industry from Twitch and Steam via python, Twitch API, and Power BI

<u>Projects</u>

Customer Churn Classification

Performed data cleaning, and feature engineering using Python's Scikit-learn and TensorFlow to classify the churn rate of Telco customers using supervised learning models such as Light GBM, Logistic Regression, and Support Vector Classifier.

Marketing Data Analytics

Analyzed user data for an e-learning platform using Python's NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, and Matplotlib libraries to generate insights for increasing user engagement by tracking web KPIs such as churn rate, bounce rate, page exits, visits, searches, etc.

Tableau Web Application

Developed a web application with map visualizations using Tableau API of housing violations in PG county, MD for prospective homeowners. The server uses the Fetch API to GET information from PG County open-data portal visualized with Tableau.

SQL Database Design

Collected data on the original 1999 Yu-Gi-Oh cards, created tables and an Entity Relationship Diagram, and developed a database using MySQL Workbench. Also, created varied views and queries to pull attributes as per user needs.